[MUSIC]
Hello and welcome.
I'm Andrei Panko and
I will be demonstrating to
you how to create
troubles and how to solve them
when you're dealing
with Shopify integrations.
It's an overview session.
It includes also
functionality which existed
before, but now we have
even more troubleshooting things
which is actually very
difficult to demonstrate because
we also dramatically
increased stability of the product.
But I work hard to
actually create some issues.
So we will take a look how
troubleshoot things using logging functionality.
What is Shopify API
versioning and what impact it has or
actually do not have on us
if you do all the things right.
And how to troubleshoot
most noisy areas from the past.
It's order synchronization
and fulfillment synchronization.
Let's take a look.
Now we are in
Business Central and let's try to
synchronize something and
see how to deal with problems.
We start with customers and I
would like to push some customers to Shopify.
I will synchronize
and oops nothing happens.
I expected at least
one customer to go there.
What is wrong?
Probably the best advice or
standard advice is to explore logs.
I will go to Shopify logs.
Log entries.
So many, so many.
It is so difficult to deal with them.
Not anymore.
So first of all, this is like how
it used to look in the previous version.
With the new upgrade, the
default view looks a bit better.
I will remove personalization, which
I made to look at as the previous version.
And now you can see
that I have additional columns.
First of all, I have columns which show
some information
about request and response.
So at least now I can see that.
Here I'm trying to
create some customer data.
It will help me to distinguish
between, for example, location synchronization or
order synchronization
or product synchronization.
The second interesting nuance is
the checkbox, which shows if this specific
synchronization attempt had error or not.
And of course, it's
more interesting to look at
the entries which
mark as entries with errors.
All right. So we're logging
additional information and some strange things can
happen on either Shopify
site or on Business Central site.
And if we receive status code
500, something wrong was on Shopify site.
In this case, in
this case, it's better to
ask Shopify to
support through troubleshoot.
And to help you to talk to
Shopify support, you need to use a request ID.
It will help them to identify
specific request response dramatically faster and
provide more detailed information to you.
So this is information which you need
to use when interacting with Shopify support.
But if error is 200, then
you should be with something else.
Let's explore the response.
Now many responses contain a
section which is called user error.
It means that when we
try to submit some data to
Shopify as users,
something didn't work very well.
So for example, field phone
rejected content which we were sending.
And it says enter a valid phone number.
So particularly
Shopify checks the phones.
And what phone do we send there?
Yeah, it doesn't look
as a very well formatted phone.
So troubleshooting is very simple.
We will just go and
edit the phone and try again.
But before doing so,
let's ask ourselves a question.
If we know which errors
are bad and which records were
succeeded and which failed, do
we really need to lock all of them?
And the answer is maybe.
Let's take a look
at the Shopify shop card.
And you can see that
now logging mode transformed
from the boolean on
and off into the option field.
Where you can of course have it
completely disabled, fully enabled or special new
mode which is now default one error only.
So in this case, it will be
sending dramatically less number of errors.
Let's go back to Shopify log entries.
Delete them all just for clarity.
And activate error only mode.
Right?
Now we will go to customers.
We will fix our customer.
Very simply, I will
just remove these values.
And let's go to Shopify,
customers and try to do the synchronization now.
Okay, we can see that
customer was created and what about logs?
It is empty, so it's not polluted.
It's like very good.
If you're still getting errors,
of course, they will be accumulated here.
And it makes also sense to
clean up them from time to time.
Not manually as I did, but you can
see that we are using retention policies now.
And we include the Shopify log entries by
default, so they will
be cleaned up every month.
You don't need probably
entries which are more than one month old.
Also, we have the same one, but
disabled by default for Shopify data capture.
We will talk about
this feature a bit later.
All right, log is clean.
But some people who troubleshoot it
for some time, they already know that customer
synchronization
already provided user errors part.
What about other areas?
Yes, we modified queries.
Now they also, in
many cases, if not always,
return user error
part if user error happened.
Let's take a look,
for example, to products.
And let's try to submit some product.
Home, add items.
I will be synchronizing item 118.
Let me pick the store and click OK.
So, 11, 18, and it failed.
Why? Let's check our log entries.
Very nice.
Only one entry.
And it obviously has issue.
So, let's take a look at the details.
Shopify error? No.
Something else? Yes.
Do we have user error section? Yes.
It complains about field SKU.
SKU can't be blank.
Let's go to the shops and take a look.
Yes, SKU mapping field is empty.
Then, of course, the SKU field will be
blank when we're exporting data to Shopify.
But why? It is a problem right now.
So, now we are not
troubleshooting things for
real, but we are
introducing the new functionality.
Be aware that already before
this release in one of the minor updates,
we enabled full support for
business central fulfillment service.
So, it's a separate mode how Shopify
allows you to work with external systems.
So, you can configure Shopify
to use on fulfillment and locations.
And in this case, it still works.
You can have
multiple of them and synchronize.
Or in Shopify, you do not care about
locations at all
because fulfillment locations, etc.
will be handled on your system.
And in this case, it
will be business central.
So, now, how does
it look on Shopify side?
Let's open the Shopify admin and explore.
I will open some product and scroll down.
And you can see that in
inventory tab, you can have different options.
It allows you to choose either business
central fulfillment
service or multiple locations.
And if you choose
business central fulfillment
service, it actually
requires you to have SKU defined.
So, SKU can't be blank.
So, it says exactly
here in the UI and the same
information we
received in the business central.
Why?
Because in the
Shopify shop locations, we have a
toggle which defines
how do we create a new product.
If you activate the toggle
on business central fulfillment,
then new products
created on Shopify will be
assigned to business
central fulfillment locations.
And hence, they require a SKU field.
Now, back to troubleshooting area.
What do we see also
in the Shopify shop card?
Something new.
And this is a very scary
field which is called end of support.
You should not be afraid
of it because I will explain.
Shopify also evolving pretty quickly.
So, every quarter they
release a new version of the API.
So, four times per
year, there is a new version.
And each version
is supported for one year.
Okay?
So, and we try to keep up.
We always update the
recent versions or current versions.
So, it works in the
latest business central releases.
Or we also update if
necessary during minor updates.
So, if you upgrade in
your business central regularly,
you also receive the upgraded version of
business central
Shopify connector as well.
So, in this case, you're always good.
So, end of support
will be like a year ahead.
But we figured it out that some people
stuck with the old
version of business central.
And they were using
Shopify with unsupported API.
And Shopify actually
flagged our app as having troubles.
And this information
was displayed to like everybody.
Not only to people who
were using old API version.
That's confusing
and unpleasant and creates
wrong impression for
all good upgraded customers.
So, now we have a
better information about what
will happen if you do
not upgrade in business central.
The old versions will stop working.
Just upgrade as normal.
Also, it makes sense to remind you
about when you're trying to do troubleshooting
about background and
foreground synchronizations.
Let me demonstrate.
If synchronization is running in the
foreground, then you don't actually see any
feedback when you
execute synchronization.
Like customer sync, nothing happens.
You go to system create
job queue and it executes there.
And if error happens, it is there.
But if you experience some problems,
sometimes it's easier to
explore it in the foreground.
Let me imitate very basic problem.
I will just disable integration.
And now when I click on
seeing customers, something bad happens.
It will be in the logging system, but I
would like to catch
error in detail right away.
In this case, I
will disable the ground sync,
which is owned by
default and try to do it again.
OK, in this case, I get the error and
I can copy all details, including cold stack.
Of course, in this
case, it's very primitive, but
in some scenarios, we
know it was not that simple.
All right.
Let's activate our synchronization back.
Another advice about
troubleshooting and connectivity, you might want to have
Shopify admin already up and running
in the same browser, probably in the same tab.
Then in this case, the authorization
happens smoothly and you are not redirected to
a separate browser tab,
which is sometimes faster and easier.
All right.
Now let's go and
troubleshoot something business
process related, sales
orders and then fulfillments.
So how do you do order synchronization?
Let's go to the list of orders.
I have plenty of them.
And you can usually do, I think,
orders from Shopify, which is a standard pattern.
But what if
something doesn't work as expected
or you need more
control on what is happening?
Take a look at this filter.
Shopify orders to import.
It's not just a filtering opportunity.
It is in reality the buffer table.
And I will show you how to use it.
Let's create some troubles.
For example, let's
remove this specific order because
it is missing for some
reason and it's not in the sink.
I am trying to troubleshoot this problem.
I will go to the search and orders to
import, like the same as this filter string,
and it will open me
another table, another list.
And it has an action
which says get orders to import.
If I will press it, I will get orders
which were modified after some specific date.
You can reset this date if
necessary from the Shopify admin.
Or you can go to
Shopify and modify slightly order.
For example, you can
change the tag or add node.
All right. Now I got my order here.
Now I can select the shop.
You know that it's
possible to connect multiple business
central Shopify shop
cards to the single Shopify account.
For which reason? Probably because
you are parsing the orders differently.
Bases, for example,
by tags or something else.
That's why I need to instruct into which
shop I'm going to
import this specific order.
And then I will
press import selected orders.
So here the import
process was very fast and simple.
It just gets the
header with a couple of fields.
But once I will press
get orders to import, system
will start to download
additional information in a moment.
And if something bad happens,
you will see has error field here.
And in the bottom
system will show the error details.
It also sometimes
helpful to troubleshoot.
I didn't manage to reproduce it anymore.
Probably because we
solved this one issue already.
But useful to know.
So import selected order.
And now we start to
import additional information.
Header, fully payments, transactions,
shipments, lines,
returns, refunds, like a lot of stuff.
And then my order was added.
And now it's time to explore.
And sometimes you can ask question
like where this information is coming from.
So now you can, it was also
possible before to inspect the data.
For example, retrieve Shopify data.
Now you can see like what
exactly we received from Shopify.
So now you can understand if it's
problem about data which we received from Shopify
or the way how it
was parsed by connector.
So this is for header.
This is for lines.
Also for shipping cost.
You can see inspect or transactions.
Also inspect or even fulfillment.
And fulfillment by
the way receives the whole
page card so you can
get some additional details.
Not something you would
explore just out of curiosity.
But if doing some
troubleshooting makes sense to have
it available right away
instead of exploring tables.
Another useful hint on what to do if
you want to troubleshoot stuff and compare
Shopify via Business
Central data is to go to Shopify.
Let's go to orders.
Let's find the order.
And then in the URL you just add JSON.
Now you can see like
representation of Shopify.
For example, how discounts are allocated.
It also might be helpful to understand.
For example, if you are missing the item
variant code, you might
be curious like why it's all.
Is it because we didn't receive it
from Shopify or it does not exist in Shopify?
That happened.
And this trick helps to
solve confusion and help you
to understand whom to
contact for additional support.
Is it Shopify or your
Microsoft partner and Microsoft?
All right.
So now let's do something bad
to create problems with fulfillment.
All right.
Let's navigate to Shopify
store and let's buy some chair.
Buy it now.
It will be Denmark.
It will be our
favorite customer, Cloud J.
Lawson, who lives in
Denmark and buying free chair with
some shipping cost, but it
doesn't matter right now in reality.
We just need to have some order
which we will import and then break.
OK. Now we have order.
Time to import it.
So sync orders from Shopify.
OK, good.
I have multiple orders already waiting.
All right.
OK. I have order ready.
And it's created in Business
Central, so it's ready to be shipped.
Let's open it.
Post shipment should be enough.
But before we will send it
to Shopify, something bad happens.
Somebody in Shopify
admin, probably administrator or
responsible person, for some
reason, Mark is order as fulfilled.
OK.
So it was also fulfilled here.
Now if I will be
trying to synchronize shipment
from Business
Central to Shopify, it will fail.
For good reason.
Let's click sync shipments to Shopify.
OK.
And let's go and
explore the Rolleit Center.
So in Rolleit Center, you can see
Shopify activities, which was here before.
Now you can see that we have two fields
demonstrating the
status of shipment synchronization.
If something pending
shipment or something failed.
And now this is actually actionable one.
So you can explore what is the problem.
So let's imagine that we already
explored our Shopify order, the data.
We see that fulfillment is
for some reason Mark as closed.
So we go back to Shopify admin.
Orders.
And cancel fulfillment.
OK.
Because it was
marked as fulfilled by mistake.
Right?
Because we are waiting
shipment from Business Central.
Back to Business Central.
And then we have update document.
And now we have Shopify tab,
which actually shows Shopify fulfillment ID.
And it can be 0, -1 if it's
some error, or the actual value.
If it has an actual value, then all good.
Don't touch it.
And it's actually non-editable.
But you can change -1 to 0.
It's documented.
It's done confusing on purpose.
And now this document moves from
shipment errors to unprocessed shipments.
Now we can try again.
I think shipments to Shopify.
And it was
successfully passed to Shopify.
So what we saw.
Logs.
Now more powerful
because more details if necessary.
And less details and
space usage if not necessary.
So this is dramatically cleaner.
Shopify API versioning.
No need to worry.
Just stay updated.
And then we saw how to
troubleshoot order synchronization
and fulfillment synchronization.
Using additional details like
activities part on the wallet center.
And data captured during
synchronization between Shopify and Business Central.
I hope it will make your work easier.
But I hope you will not
need all these tools because
connector is again more and more stable.
And less issues are happening with it.
You can find the list of
valuable resources on this slide.
And if you partner, remember that
you can join Yammer, the first link on here.
And here we have a group
about Shopify connector only.
So if you have questions,
proposals or something to discuss,
register ID and join
the Yammer to discuss it.
Thank you for watching.
Let's stay connected.